Mojo-Mojo-Mojo-Spy
Mojo-Mojo-Mojo-Spy
This world is colorful and bright
這個世界五彩斑斓
But what truly dazzles our sight
真正恰恰迷惑我们的眼
Use your heart to see it clear
用你的心认真去看
The truth is always near
发现真相就在不远
Hey you good or bad, truly
Hey you good or bad 真正恰恰
Can't escape the soul's smoky haze
逃不出这心灵的灰烟
Gather all your courage, be brave
带上你的所有勇敢
Maybe you can save the world today
也许就能拯救这世间
Mojo Mojo Mojo Spy
Mojo Mojo Mojo Spy
The vanished tears
消失的眼泪
I am honored to announce that the first stop of the Angel's Tears gem world tour
我荣幸地向大家宣布天使之泪宝石世界巡回展的第一站
Will be held at the Banana Museum in this city
将在本市的香蕉博物馆展出
That's what I'm after
我要的就是它
Locky Qi, hurry up!
齐乐天 你快点嘛
I stayed up late watching Smile Match last night
我昨天看微笑对对碰到好晚
And you dragged me out early this morning
一大早就被你拽起来
You're so mean
你好凶哦
There's a really cool exhibition today
今天有特别好看的展览哦
Angel's Tears
天使之泪
Boring
沒意思
I'm definitely not going
我肯定不去
Go ahead.
去嘛
No way.
一定不去
Come on, come on.
去嘛去嘛
Absolutely not.
絕對不去
Please, please, please.
去嘛去嘛去嘛
But if you buy me ice cream, I'll go with you.
但如果你請我吃冰淇淋的話我就跟你去
Ice cream's here!
冰淇淋來囉
Hey, watch where you're going!
你这人没长眼睛啊
Can't you drive properly?
到底会不会开车啊
You're driving me crazy!
气死我了啊
Sorry, please step back.
对不起 请往后退
Everyone, stay calm.
大家镇定一点儿
Thanks.
谢谢
Step back and cooperate with us.
往后退 配合我们的工作
I'm going in anyway.
我偏偏要进
Let us in!
让我们进去
Awesome!
好棒啊
They're all flying!
他们都飞起来了
So many cute exhibits!
好多可爱的展品哟
Jingjing loves it here!
菁菁好喜欢这里
So adorable.
好可爱
This in front of us should be the Angel's Tears, right?
我们前面这个就应该是天使之类了吧
Wait, where's the gem?
奇怪 宝石在哪
Stop right there.
站住
What do you think you're doing?
你们要干嘛
Let me go.
放开我
What are you doing?
你们要干什么
Just as I expected.
果然不出所料
The criminal will always return to the crime scene.
罪犯一定会再次回到案发现场的
Who are you?
你是谁啊
Kid, you have eyes but can't see Mount Tai.
你小子真是有眼不识泰山
I am the legendary detective who strikes fear into criminals across the alert zone—
我就是威震警戒令犯罪分子闻风丧胆的神探
Inspector Sima.
司马刚
What lousy detective?
什么什么烂神探
Let me go.
放开我
How dare you insult a police officer!
你竟敢侮辱警务人员
Hold him tight, don't let him escape.
快抓稳，别让他跑了
Huh? Why them?
嗯？怎么是他们
So young and already on the path of theft.
小小年纪就走向盗窃这条不归路
How did your parents raise you?
你们家长是怎么教育你们的
You've got the wrong people.
你们抓错人了
Please let them go.
请放开他们
Who are you?
你是谁
What makes you say we've got the wrong people?
凭什么说我们抓错人了
I'm international detective Jimmy Chen.
我是国际侦探陈嘉明
You've arrested my little nephew.
你们抓的是我的小侄子
Stop messing around.
别再胡闹了
I warned you before—
我早就提醒过你
Your mind isn't cut out for solving cases.
你的头脑不适合推理案件
Yes.
是
Detective Chen, welcome.
陈侦探欢迎你
Sorry to trouble you again.
这次又要麻烦你了
[Shoving sounds]
[推搡的声音]
Wah wah wah, Uncle!
呜呜呜 老舅
You bunch of bad guys!
你们这群坏蛋
Why are you picking on us?
为什么要欺负我们
No, no, no, it wasn't me!
不不不 不是我
Locky Qi, you've got it wrong.
齐乐天 你误会了
They're police officers.
他们是警察
Here's what happened:
事情是这样的
Last night, the precious gem, Angel's Tears,
昨天晚上珍贵的宝石天使之泪
had just been delivered to the exhibition hall when it mysteriously vanished.
刚刚被运到展览馆就神秘失踪了
The police are investigating.
警察们正在调查之中
You barged in,
你们闯了进来
so of course you're suspects.
当然就要怀疑你们咯
Let me introduce you.
我介绍一下
This is Mr. K, the agent for this exhibition.
这位是代理本次展览的Mr.K
Hello.
你们好
And this is the head of security here, Lei Jie.
这位是本馆的保安负责人雷杰
Greetings, everyone.
大家好
The vault door holding the gem
装放宝石的保险库大门
requires both of their personal keys to open.
同时需要他们两个人的贴身钥匙才能打开
But on the night of the incident,
但是当晚案发时
both of them were elsewhere.
两个人都身在别处
If the gem can't be returned to my country...
如果宝石不能带回我的祖国
What should I do?
我该怎么办
Jimmy,
佳明
what do you think?
你有什么见解
Tricking these surveillance devices
要骗过这些监控设备
isn't that hard.
也不是什么难事
I just connected my computer to the museum's mainframe
我刚刚用电脑连接了展览馆的主机
and found some issues.
发现了一些问题
Everyone, come take a look.
大家过来看一下
Where's Jingjing?
菁菁呢
Jingjing,
菁菁
where are you?
你在哪啊
That guy looks really familiar.
这个人看起来好眼熟啊
Hey, isn't he the jerk who hit me with his car?
啊 他不是开车撞我的坏蛋吗
What's he doing here?
他在这干嘛
Target locked.
目标已锁定
Located at twelve o'clock.
位于十二点为止
Copy that.
收到
After investigation,
经过调查
I found that a hacker broke into the mainframe controlling the museum's vault.
我发现有黑客侵入了负责展览馆保险库的主机
His exact goal is still unclear,
他的具体目的还不能够确定
but I suspect this hacker
但是我怀疑这个入侵的黑客
is connected to the gem theft case.
应该就与这起宝石失窃案有关
The hacker is starting to break in again.
黑客又开始入侵了
Everyone, stay calm.
大家不要慌
I'll deploy the fireproof vehicle to deal with him.
我这就放出防火战车来对付他
So this is what a hacker battle looks like?
这就是黑客之间的战斗吗
What's that sneaky villain up to?
这个坏蛋 鬼鬼祟祟的想干什么
Hmm, he's waltzing right in.
嗯 大摇大摇的进去了
The poor intruder—I've already cornered him.
可怜的入侵者 已经被我逼得无路可走
Wow, Detective Chen really knows his way around hackers.
没想到陈侦探对网络黑客这么有研究啊
Haha, it's nothing, nothing at all.
哈哈 这不算什么 这不算什么
Ah, the hacker got away!
啊 黑客逃走了
Cool, successfully hacked the mainframe. The vault door's about to open.
酷 已成功入侵电脑主机 保险库大门即将开启
This kid's got some skills.
这小子还挺能耐的
He actually made the door open by itself.
居然能让大门自动开启
He's definitely up to no good.
肯定要做坏事
I need to find Uncle fast.
我得赶紧去找老舅去
Jingjing, this is urgent.
菁菁现在情况紧急
Go get Uncle right now.
快去把老舅叫来
Jingjing.
菁菁
Juice.
果汁
All gone.
喝光了
Is this enough?
这些够了吗
I order you to find Uncle immediately.
我命你立刻把老舅找出来
Roger that!
遵命！
He's already out.
他已经出来了
What now?
怎么办
I really don't want to be alone and lonely.
特别不想 一个人孤单寂寞
But life
但是人生
can sometimes be a little unhappy.
难免会有些不快乐
Saying goodbye to today
告别今天
always feels a bit sad.
总是让人觉得失落
Look at tomorrow
看看明天
waving to me from the horizon.
在地平线向我招手
Every day, as the sun rises and sets,
每天就在日升日落
I turn time into more dreams.
转进时间幻想更多
Looking forward to every second and moment of life,
期待生命中每秒每一刻
bright eyes are sparkling.
明亮的眼睛在闪烁
A smile that greets the sunlight,
迎着阳光的笑容
stepping through the silent crossroads.
踏破桥桥中在沉默着的路口
Drop dead.
都死吧
You are now the prime suspect.
你现在是最大的嫌疑犯
Please come with us.
请跟我们走一趟吧